Hi, everyone. I am here today to show you how
大家好 今天我要与大家分享
an ending version of the Bikeshare Project could work.
共享单车项目的最终版本是如何运行的
And to do that,
为此
we're going to look at two different examples because there are actually
我们将会看到两个例子
multiple ways that you could build something that would
实际上我们可以通过许多方式
pass the rubric items specific for this project.
来通过这个项目的审阅标准
And, essentially, there's a template that's provided to you,
并且 重要的是 我们为你提供了一个模板
but you should feel free to change that template however you would like to.
但你可以随意改变这个模板
So the function definitions and things that are provided in there,
这个模板里提供的函数、定义等数据
you can use as they are,
你都可以直接使用
but if something doesn't make sense to how you imagine you're ending project working,
但如果有些内容并不适用于你理想中项目的最终版本
feel free to change the inputs to it,
请随意改变它的输入
change what it returns.
或是它返回的内容
The main thing is that you get an ending prototype,
重点是你需要得到一个最终的原型
an ending portfolio project working in a way where
一个最终版本的项目组合
it interacts with the user and provides the information that are asked within the rubric.
它可以和用户互动 并提供审阅标准中要求的信息
So with that, I'm going to take a look at two solutions.
因此 我们来看看这两个答案
So one is the solution.py file,
第一个是 solution.py 文件
and the other is a bikeshare.py file,
另一个是 bikeshare.py 文件
and these are both correct solutions to what
这两个答案都是正确的
a final project might look like for the Bikeshare Project.
都是 Bikeshare 项目的最终版本
If we were to run the bikeshare.py project,
如果我们运行 bikeshare.py 项目
it says, "Which city would you like to see data from?"
它会提示“你希望查看哪个城市的数据？”
And let's say I say Chicago.
让我们输入芝加哥
And then says, "Would you like to filter the data by month,
接着会提示“你希望按照什么标准来筛选数据？月份？星期？”
day, both, or not at all?"
“都选？还是都不选？”
Type none for no time filter.
我们输入 none 来取消时间筛选
You can see that this asks for each of these,
你可以看到 每一次运行都会出现这些问题
which wasn't specified in the original filter provided by
模板中提供的原始过滤器并没有出现这些
the template but this was an advanced feature that was provided in the solution.
但这是答案中提供的高阶特性
So let's say I say both,
接着我们输入 both
and it says "Which month?"
程序会提示“哪个月份”
And I'll say February.
输入 February
And then which day? Please give it as an integer.
接着选择星期请输入一个整数
Let's say 3. Cool. So it says the most popular hour
我们输入 3 很好 当你这样筛选数据时
was 17 with a count of 723 when you did this filter.
程序显示最热门的出行时间是 17 点 次数为 723 次
The total duration was this, a count of this.
总骑行时间在这里 次数在这里
The average duration was here.
平均骑行时间在这里
Again, the filter was both.
筛选条件输入的是 both
Calculated the most popular station,
接着 我们来计算最热门的车站
so the most popular start station was here with a count of 122.
那么 最热门的起始车站在这里 次数是 122 次
The most popular end station was here with a count of 110.
最热门的结束车站在这里 次数是110 次
And, again, the filter was both.
筛选条件输入的也是 both
So you can see that this is one potential solution for this,
你可以看到这是本项目的标准答案之一
where it's telling me how long it took,
它能告诉我花费的时间
and it gives me a whole bunch of other information.
还有许多其他信息
It says, "Would you like to see individual trip data?"
现在程序提示”你想查看个人骑行数据吗？“
I say yes, and it gives me some information back.
选择是 它将返回一些信息
And then I can say no, and it says,
接着我选择否 它显示
"Would you like to restart?" And I'll say no.
”你想重新开始吗？“ 我将会选择否
Cool. So that is one potential solution to this.
很好 所以这是答案之一
Let's take a look at another one in a different example.
我们来看看另一个例子
It says, "Which one would you like to explore?"
程序提示 ”你想查看哪个城市的情况？“
So you can see they've built in this thing where it says,
所以 你可以看到这个程序设置了这样的提示内容
"It looks like you want to hear about Washington.
”看起来你想了解华盛顿的数据“
If that's not true, restart the program."
”如果这是错误的请重启程序“
So they built in a check,
因此 程序中设置了一个检查机制
where it says it sort of builds in this filter of what they're going to do.
通过过滤器程序会判定它将完成的操作
You can see that that was sort of done in the end of that other example,
你可以在另一个例子的结尾看到 这是如何实现的
but both of those are acceptable.
但这两者都是可以接受的
"Would you like to filter by day,
”你希望按照月份还是星期筛选数据？“
month or not at all?"
”还是不筛选数据？“
So let's just say,
那么在这里
in this case, let's do month.
我们选择月份
"Which month do you want?"
”你想选择几月？“
May.
五月
Cool. And so you can see that this one started calculating all those statistics,
很好 你可以看到程序已经开始计算这些数据了
and you can see it was a little bit faster.
它的速度更快
The way that it shows the information is a little bit different.
呈现信息的方式也有些不同
So you can see it says,
你可以看到程序提示
"What's the breakdown of users?"
”用户的分类是什么？“
And that looks like this,
它显示这些信息
and "What is the most popular station?"
还有 ”最热门的车站是什么？“
So the most popular start and end station and here's the count.
那么 这里是最热门的起始车站和结束车站 这里是计数
You can see what's the total traveling time done,
你可以问总骑行时间是什么
and it gives it back in a little bit different format.
它返回的信息格式有一点不同
"What's the most popular hour of the day?"
”一天中最热门的出行时间是什么？“
It says 5.
它返回 5
"What's the most popular day for traveling?" It's Wednesday.
”一周中最热门的出行时间是哪一天？“ 是周三
So you can see that this one actually gave you a little bit less up front in terms of
所以你可以看到这里显示的信息更少
like how you're filtering and that was
根据筛选数据的方式不同
because I only filtered by month and the other one filtered by both.
这是因为在这里我选择按月份筛选 而在刚才的例子中我选择的是月份和星期
So it says, "Would you like to restart?"
接着程序显示”你是否想重新开始“
Let's just do a restart on this one.
让我们重新开始
So it says, "Would you like to filter by which city?"
程序显示”你想筛选哪个城市的数据？“
I'll say Chicago, and let's say I filter by day.
我们输入芝加哥 并按星期筛选数据
So here notice that it says you can filter by this
请注意 这里显示你可以这样筛选
based on not a number but like on one of these letter values.
并不是输入数字 而是这些字母值
So I'm going to say Thursday,
那么我们选择星期四
and then it calculates the information for me based on that filter.
接着 它开始根据这些筛选条件为我计算信息
So again these are just two different ways to show the information at the end but,
再一次 我们可以看到在最后这里 有两种显示信息的方式
in general, it needs to be interactive,
一般来说它需要是互动式的
and it needs to show the statistics that are specified based on the rubric.
而且它需要提供审阅标准规定的信息
And those are really the only two restrictions.
这也是唯一的两个限制
So it should meet the rubric by giving
它需要满足审阅标准
an interactive experience and calculating the statistics necessary,
也就是提供互动式体验和计算必要数据
but the template should just serve as a guide,
不过这里的模板只是起指导作用
and you should feel free to change that however
你可以随意修改它
you think you want your program to interact with the user.
来使程序按照你的想法同用户互动
Build in as much interactivity as you want to,
请按你自己的喜好配置交互内容
and you should feel comfortable being creative in your solution.
并使你的答案具有创意
I hope this is helpful. Thanks for joining me.
我希望这能给你带来帮助 感谢观看
Good luck with your projects.
祝你好运